Guide to the oH Project transcripts of recorded interviews: Oral Histories of HIV/AIDS in Houston, Harris County, and Southeast Texas, 2015-2021 MS 642
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
The oH Project collection: Oral Histories of HIV/AIDS in Houston, Harris County, and Southeast Texas
2015-2021
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Montrose Center
MS 642
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
66 Gigabytes Audio stored in Woodson's nearline environment as MS0642aip_001, MS0642aip_002, and MS0642aip_003.
Oral history interviews in audio and transcript format, including interview consent forms filed with the interviews. The primary subject matter is the experience of at least 100 long term survivors, physicians, activists, religious and political leaders and others impacted by HIV / AIDS epidemic in Houston, Harris County and Southeast Texas.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 2015, the Oral History Project's goal is to collect, preserve, and make available the experiences of at least 100 long term survivors, physicians, activists, religious and political leaders and others impacted by HIV / AIDS epidemic in Houston, Harris County and Southeast Texas, with special emphasis on those who experienced the early years of the epidemic. Founding partners of the project include Legacy Community Health, Montrose Center, and the Woodson Research Center, Rice University. It is the policy of The oH Project to redact the names of third parties in reference to their HIV / AIDS status or sexual orientation unless The oH Project has written consent from the third party to be named or proof that the person has shared his or her HIV / AIDS status and/or sexual orientation in a public record. Interviewee donor agreements which document the interviewee's agreement for internet access of their interview are maintained by the Woodson Research Center.
Scope and Contents
Oral history interviews in audio and transcript format, including interview consent forms filed with the interviews. The primary subject matter is the experience of at least 100 long term survivors, physicians, activists, religious and political leaders and others impacted by HIV / AIDS epidemic in Houston, Harris County and Southeast Texas.
Conditions Governing Access
The interview transcripts are available online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/91682.
The collection is open for research with restrictions as noted. Contact woodson@rice.edu for assistance in making requests for restricted interviews.
Interviewee donor agreements are filed in the folder along with the transcript, and articulate the terms of access. Copies of these agreements are also filed in digital format with the electronic versions of the interviews.
Requests for access to the audio portion of this interview may be submitted to woodson@rice.edu and will be considered for privacy concerns by The oH Project board. Please include these identifier numbers in your request: MS0642aip_001 and MS0642aip_002.
One additional interview is restricted until the death of the interviewee, and is being held in the collection's control folder.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received from the board of the oH Project, 2016-2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
LGBTQ people; Health care and medicine; Women
Document Types
Oral histories; digital audio formats; transcripts
Subjects (Corporations)
Legacy Community Health
- Series I: Interviews (physical copies with links to online transcripts), 2015-2021
  - Aldape, Theresa, 2019-07-24 (Box 1)
  - Aguries, Cynthia V., 2021-07-30 (Box 1)
  - Belcher, Rosalind, 2018-09-29 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Transcript is available only for use onsite at Woodson Research Center, and may not be placed online, by direction of the interviewee.
  - Benson, David L., 2016-05-20 (Box 1)
  - Boyle, Ardry "Skeet", 2019-04-23 (Box 1)
  - Brannon, Michael, 2017-02-01 (Box 1)
  - Caldwell, Katy, 2017-06-22 (Box 1)
  - Cleary, Dan, 2018-02-22 (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Marion E., 2016-11-22 (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Sue, 2021-03-29 (Box 1)
  - David, Amber, 2016-08-17 (Box 1)
  - Dieter, Donna and Allan, 2018-02-24 (Box 1)
  - Doyle, JD, 2019-09-03 (Box 1)
  - Edmonson, Andrew, 2017-01-07 (Box 1)
  - Fitzgibbons, Stella, 2016-09-09 (Box 1)
  - Fuentes, Joe, 2016-08-15 (Box 1)
  - Gardner, Glenda, 2016-07-07 (Box 1)
  - Gill, Don, 2016-04-12 (Box 1)
  - Golden, Michael, 2019-10-05 (Box 1)
  - Grimes, Richard, 2019-06-14 (Box 1)
  - Gustafson, Paul, 2019-09-11 (Box 1)
  - Hergenroeder, Bob, 2016-12-16 (Box 1)
  - Hill, Ray, 2016-09-29 (Box 1)
  - Isbell, Frances, 2019-12-12 (Box 1)
  - Jobe, Randall, 2019-06-28 (Box 1)
  - Jones, Robert A., 2016-08-03 (Box 1)
  - Jones, William "Bill", 2016-01-05 (Box 1)
  - Katine, Mitchell, 2016-10-29 (Box 1)
  - Keever, Carmon Brian, 2015-09-26 (Box 1)
  - Kerr, Christopher, 2017-07-15 (Box 1)
  - Kline, Mark, 2019-09-03 (Box 1)
  - Kotarba, Joseph A., 2019-05-22 (Box 1)
  - Leonard, Amy, 2016-07-13 (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Shirley, 2015-10-05 (Box 2)
  - Lindsay, Jon, 2019-10-30 (Box 2)
  - Lovell, Sue, 2017-06-13 (Box 2)
  - Malone, Ken, 2019-03-12 (Box 2)
  - Mandel, Barry, 2018-10-05 (Box 2)
  - Mills, Rodney (Box 2)
  - Mizwa, Michael, 2019-09-09 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Lois J., 2016-02-19 (Box 2)
  - More, Scot Alan, 2018-03-10 (Box 2)
  - Nelson, Jane, 2017-03-15 (Box 2)
  - O'Doherty, Denise, 2017-04-08 (Box 2)
  - Onaiwu, Morenike Giwa, 2021-09-10 (Box 2)
  - Parker, Annise, 2017-01-12 (Box 2)
  - Peranteau, Michael, 2016-05-03 (Box 2)
  - Rios, Adan, 2017-01-12 (Box 2)
  - Robison, Dr. Ann J., 2017-07-17 (Box 2)
  - Rodriguez, Pete, 2015-12-17 (Box 2)
  - Roland, Eric, 2016-12-06 (Box 2)
  - Sampey, Danielle, 2019-01-22 (Box 2)
  - Schrader, Shannon, 2019-05-28 (Box 2)
  - Selber, Sara Speer, 2019-08-14 (Box 2)
  - Shandera, Wayne, 2019-10-26 (Box 2)
  - Sims, Nancy, 2019-05-09 (Box 2)
  - Staggs, Frank M., Jr., 2016-01-19 (Box 2)
  - Thorp, Gretchen V., 2018-10-23 (Box 2)
  - Turner, Bruce, 2019-08-01 (Box 2)
  - Tyer, Lynne, 2016-05-25 (Box 2)
  - Valka, Jean Lanclos, 2019-02-28 (Box 2)
  - Vargas, Steven, 2017-03-07 (Box 2)
  - Vergel, Nelson, 2019-06-19 (Box 2)
  - Ware, Chella, 2019-08-08 (Box 2)
  - Zuckerbrod, Steven, 2018-04-21 (Box 2)
- Series II: Audio (restricted access)
  - Audio files, group 1, 2015
    General
    This digital content is stored in a nearline environment at the Woodson Research Center. Contact staff at woodson@rice.edu with the Identifier # MS0642aip_001, and please be aware of the following access terms.
    Content Restrictions: Privacy restrictions on ALL AUDIO, requiring written permission from the oH Project board for access.
    Most interview transcripts have been cleared for presentation online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/91682, including: Benson, Fitzgibbons, Fuentes, Gardner, Gill, Hill, Jones, Katine, Keever, Moore, Peranteau, Staggs, Tyer, Rodriguez.
    Transcripts which are restricted to reading room access only are: Leonard, Lewis.
  - Audio files, group 2, 2016-2017
    Privacy restrictions on ALL AUDIO, requiring written permission from the oH Project board for access. Write to woodson@rice.edu requesting access. Pending approval for access, these files are stored in the Woodson Research Center's nearline environment at identifier # MS0642aip_002.
    Audio files in this group include: Roland, David, Vargas, Mills, Hergenroeder, Brannon, Parker, Nelson, Rios, O'Doherty, Coleman, Robison, Kerr, and Dieter.
    Interview transcripts for this group are available online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/91682.
  - Audio files, group 3, 2017-2019
    Privacy restrictions on ALL AUDIO, requiring written permission from the oH Project board for access. Write to woodson@rice.edu requesting access. Pending approval for access, these files are stored in the Woodson Research Center's nearline environment at identifier # MS0642aip_003.
    Audio files in this group include: Bill Jones, Edmondson, Lovell, Caldwell, Cleary, More, Zuckerbrod, Belcher, Mandel, Ware (also administratively closed), Golden, Thorp, Sampey, Malone, Boyle, Kotarba, Schrader, Grimes, Jobe.